actioncoach.com 2019-12-23

# Privacy Policy | ActionCOACH

( _Revised: 13 June, 2018 15:43 – Vernard Mercader_ )

ActionCOACH has updated its Privacy Policy in accordance with [the European Union’s New General Data Protection Regulation Law](https://gdpr-info.eu/).

### Who we are

 **ActionCOACH** is a global Business Coaching Franchise that has served thousands of businesses and their owners since 1997. Our primary and official website is: https://www.actioncoach.com. ActionCOACH values and is committed to safeguarding your personal information. It is our desire through this policy that you understand how your personal information will be handled when submitted through the ActionCOACH website.

### The data and information we collect

ActionCOACH defines “Personal Information” as any identifying information of a website visitor that opts-in through our contact forms. This information is not limited to:

  * Your name;
  * postal address;
  * telephone number;
  * your website URL, if any;
  * general company/business name and/or other information;
  * your e-mail address;
  * the time you send the enquiry;
  * and The IP Address of the machine you used to send the enquiry

By default, ActionCOACH.com does not collect any personal data about visitors until they have interacted and submitted their information in any contact form. Non-personal and technical data (such as cookies) are only retained in actioncoach.com in a single session. After you close the browser, all of your information saved by cookies will be discarded.

### How we collect data

We collect the e-mail addresses of those who communicate with us via e-mail, information voluntarily provided by the consumer, such as survey information and/or site registrations.

Upon confirming to have read and agreed to our privacy policy & terms of use and submitting your information, our sales, operations, or marketing team will collect your information, along with a statement that will read as follows:

> I, < _Your full name_ >, in accordance with the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation Laws (if applicable to me), have read and agreed to ActionCOACH’s Privacy Policy and Terms of Service, and I hereby give my consent that they can contact me through the means I provided in the website and receive any kind of marketing information or advertising.

Personal data is not just created by your interactions with our website. Personal data is also generated from technical processes such as contact forms, comments, cookies, analytics, and third-party embeds.

#### Comments

If present, ActionCOACH will retain your comments on our website if you posted it at your discretion. Please bear in mind that your opinion is solely yours, and is not represented nor necessarily agreed upon by the company.

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

When you voluntarily disclose your personal information on a bulletin board or in a chat area, that Personal Information can be collected and used by other users of the website. This may result in unsolicited messages or e-mails from other users or third parties.

#### Testimonials you leave for ActionCOACH

Testimonials, like comments, are posted at the user’s discretion. The site currently does not accept Testimonials to be posted directly, however, all of our testimonials are gathered from third party online sources such as Google (Reviews), Yelp, TrustPilot, etc. Whatever data the users provide on these third-party platforms will be governed by that third-party services’ privacy policy.

#### Subscription to our newsletters

ActionCOACH also collects data from our subscribers through the newsletter. We may or may not use a third party plugin to supply our newsletter script. If we do use a third party plugin, that plugin may collect user information as well.

#### Embedded content in ActionCOACH.com

Currently, our only embedded content that comes from a third-party source is **Google ReCAPTCHA** and a number of **YouTube** videos. The ReCAPTCHA engine is used for spam-prevention methods on all of our contact forms and sign-in pages. Google ReCAPTCHA does not collect information from our visitors for itself, nor does it collect it _for_ ActionCOACH. YouTube will parse information on your browser’s cookies to improve its ad services to you, but their privacy information is separate from ActionCOACH. To read more about Google Products policies, please visit [Google’s privacy policy page](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

Other embedded content in ActionCOACH comes from other ActionCOACH-developed scripts that are maintained in another location on the server. These scripts collect the same information that all contact forms collect and send them to our internal leads system called ActionLEADs.

#### Analytics and other tracking

Our website uses Google Analytics, Bing Webmaster Tools, Yandex Webmaster Tools, Facebook Pixel and LinkedIn Campaign tracking codes. We do not share any data collected from analytics with any third party company to use your information for contacting you.

#### Offline Contact Information

If you supply us with your postal address online, you will only receive the information for which you provided us with your address. Persons who supply us with their telephone numbers online will only receive telephone contact from us with information regarding orders they have placed online.

### How we use the data we collect

The information we collect is used to improve our services, used to notify consumers about updates to our services, improve our website and notify them about updates in the website. Additionally, this information may be used by us to contact consumers for marketing purposes or advertising with their consent.

 _With respect to Ad campaigns_ : We do not partner with or have special relationships with any ad serving companies.

From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our website to notify you of these changes and we will use for these new purposes only data collected from the time of the policy change forward. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our website periodically.

### Forwarding of ActionCOACH messages as referral

If you send another person an e-mail from the website referring that person to the website, any “referral” information you provide is used on a one-time basis to facilitate this communication and is not further retained by ActionCOACH.

### How long we retain your data

ActionCOACH.com does not retain any of your browser’s cookie information for more than your current session. In regards to any record collected through email and on our Leads system, you will need to request our IT support for deletion of a particular data.

### How we protect your data

Direct purchases, which often require highly sensitive information (i.e., Social Security, financial information, or user passwords) are not made from this website (www.actioncoach.com). This website has secured connection (“HTTPS” through SSL), however, we do not have submission forms that will ask or has ever asked visitors to transmit highly sensitive information. When we transfer and receive this type of sensitive information, we instruct visitors to use other website services with appropriate and trusted capabilities to handle such information ( _i.e. PayPal_ ).

 **Security of non-sensitive information** : ActionCOACH takes reasonable precautions to keep personal information secure. All personal information is subject to restricted access to prevent unauthorized access, modification or misuse. While ActionCOACH takes reasonable steps to protect your personal information once received, ActionCOACH cannot ensure or warrant the security of other (non-sensitive) Personal Information that you transmit. You transmit such information at your own risk. Once we receive such information we will use our best efforts to maintain the safekeeping of your Personal Information.

 **Opting out** : Users can opt out of any communication from all services of ActionCOACH or request to have all their data removed from our system. Please send us an email through our [contact form or call us](https://www.actioncoach.com/contact).

GDPR: European data protection law requires data about European residents which is transferred outside the European Union to be safeguarded to the same standards as if the data was in Europe.

### Data breach procedures

We will notify all of our registrants, visitors, and customers if we experience any form of data breach. This process will use e-mail, and/or social media notifications. We do not store highly sensitive information such as credit card information, social security, health information, or personal passwords. Hence, any highly sensitive information belonging to any user or visitor is not at risk.

### Release of data

Upon request, we provide site visitors with access to transaction information that we maintain about them (e.g., dates on which customers made contact, and if applicable, amounts and types of purchases), contact information (e.g., name, address, phone number) that we maintain about them , a description of information that we maintain about them. For security, we will not release information if the requester does not match the information we collected for a site visitor. We will enforce steps and procedures for verification before releasing any collected information from a user.

Be advised, that ActionCOACH will release your personal information if required to do so by law, search warrant, subpoena, or court order, with the exception of residents of the European Union, unless the court order, search warrant, or subpoena is issued by an official body of the European Union Government.

### To contact ActionCOACH Global:

You can send us an [Email](https://www.actioncoach.com/contact), or;

Write to our Postal Address:  
ActionCOACH Global North America  
5781 S Fort Apache Rd  
Las Vegas, NV 89148

You may also call us at +1 (702) 795-3188
